[
    {
        "question": "In a series RLC circuit, the phase difference between the current in the capacitor and the current in the resistor is?",
        "answers": {
            "a": " 0°",
            "b": "90°",
            "c": "180°",
            "d": "360°"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a series RLC circuit, the phase difference between the current in the inductor and the current in the resistor is?",
        "answers": {
            "a": " 0°",
            "b": "90°",
            "c": "180°",
            "d": "360°"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a series RLC circuit, the phase difference between the current in the capacitor and the current in the inductor is?",
        "answers": {
            "a": " 0°",
            "b": "90°",
            "c": "180°",
            "d": "360°"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "$X_L$ and $X_C$ have opposing effects in an RLC circuit?",
        "answers": {
            "a": "False",
            "b": "True"
        },
           
        "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "A 90 Ω resistor, a coil with 30 Ω of reactance, and a capacitor with 50 Ω of reactance are in series across a 12 V AC source. The current through the resistor is?",
        "answers": {
            "a": "9 mA",
            "b": "90 mA",
            "c": "13 mA",
            "d": "130 mA"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "A certain series RLC circuit with a 200 Hz, 15 V AC source has the following values: R = 12 Ω, C = 80 μF, and L = 10 mH. The total impedance expressed in polar form is-",
        "answers": {
            "a": "12.28 ∠12.34° Ω",
            "b": "12.57 ∠12.34° Ω",
            "c": "9.95 ∠12.34° Ω",
            "d": "12.62 ∠12.34° Ω"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "While drawing vector diagram for a series circuit, the reference vector is?",
        "answers": {
            "a": "Voltage",
            "b": "Current",
            "c": "Power",
            "d": "Phase angle"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "A capacitor having a capacitance of 20 μF is connected in series with a non-inductive resistance of 120 Ω across a 100-V, 50-Hz supply. Calculate the power?",
        "answers": {
            "a": "63.45 W",
            "b": "30.20 W",
            "c": "10.58 W",
            "d": "58.62 W"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the correct expression for the phase angle in an RLC series circuit?",
        "answers": {
            "a": "$Φ =\frac {tan^{-1}(X_L - X_C)} {R}$",
            "b": "$Φ = \frac {tan^{-1}(X_L + X_C)} {R}",
            "c": "Φ = \frac {tan^{-1}(X_L - X_C)} {Z}",
            "d": "Φ = \frac{tan^{-1}(X_L + X_C)} {Z}"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an RLC circuit, the power factor is always ____________",
        "answers": {
            "a": "Positive ",
            "b": "Negative",
            "c": "Depend on the circuit",
            "d": "Zero"
        },
        "correctAnswer": "c"
    }
]